Kalyani Ghodake

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Austin, Texas, United States

□ (+1) 818-224-9534 | Skalyanikghodake2013@gmail.com | A/kalyanighodake.com/ | M/kalyani-ghodake

Professional Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer with 4 years of experience. I am passionate about creating interactive web applications. I enjoy coding, testing and integration. Able to effectively self manage individual projects as well as collaborate as a part of a productive team.

Education

College of Engineering, Pune (COEP)

Pune

B.TECH. IN ELECTRONICS AND TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERING CGPA - 7.11

2014 - 2017

Government Polytechnic, Kolhapur (GPKP)

Kolhapur

DIPLOMA. IN ELECTRONICS AND TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERING SCORE - 91.56

2011 - 2014

Experience

Software Engineer, HSBC

Pune

REACTJS, REACT HOOKS, TYPESCRIPT, REDUX, REDUX TOOLKIT, JEST, J JENKINS, GITHUB

January 2020 - September 2021

- Worked on stand-alone deployment tool for application running on distributed environments.
- Designed new screens using ReactJS, Bootstrap, matrialUI to enhanced user experience
- Designed Dashboard which provides an aggregated view of the overall observations and vulnerabilities found in released items.
- Responsible for Integration of backend APIs with React front-end.
- Implemented unit test cases using Jest and Enzyme.

Consultant, Wipro Technologies

Pune

REACTJS, NODEJS, EXPRESSJS, REACT NATIVE, TYPESCRIPT, REDUX, JEST, PCF, GITHUB

February 2019 - January 2020

- Worked as a Software Developer to manage platform for enterprise customers to manage business, products and services for Telstra.
- Worked on Web, Mobile Web, Android and iOS platforms by implementing UI/UX designs.
- Responsible for delivering end to end quality product following the Technical designs, Development, Sanity Testing, Deployment Task.
- Designed REST APIs to integrate application with service now.
- Implemented Omniture tags into multiple services for sales analytics.
- Implemented unit test cases using Jest and Enzyme for front-end and Mocha, Chai and Sinon for backend.

Associate Consultant, Wipro Technologies

Pune

REACTJS, NODEJS, EXPRESSJS, MYSQL, NEWRELIC, PCF, GITHUB

August 2017 - January 2019

- · Worked on a dashboard which provides Business Metrics such as Lead/Cycle Time, Incidents, Code Commits.
- It provides Leadership team with continuous tracking of Agile Transformation Drive progress throughout Telstra.
- Designed UI using ReactJS, Bootstrap, ChartJS and Database schemas using Sequelize ORM
- Responsible for Integration of backend APIs with React front-end.
- Worked on Microservice Architecture using Docker and SQS consumers.
- Integrated application with NewRelic Application Monitoring Tool.

Languages and Frameworks

Languages

JAVASCRIPT, TYPESRIPT, HTML5, CSS

Frameworks and Libraries

REACTJS, REACT HOOKS, NODEJS, EXPRESSJS, REDUX, JEST, MOCHA, CHAI, SINON

KALYANI GHODAKE · RÉSUMÉ